Well, in the last video I mentioned
array dstructuring, and so it's only
natural that I now talk about object
destructuring. So, I'm going to do is
I'm going to comment out these two
lines, but I'm going to leave this um
line right here that shows how you
destructure an array. If we want to
dstructure an object, we can do it the
same way. So we would say let and then
curly braces first name comma last name
alias comma num villains caught and we
would set it equal to Batman. What we're
doing is we're saying go into Batman
pull out each of these attributes and
store them in these variables.
So on the next line I could alert alias.
If I save that and I come over here, I
get Batman. So that works about like we
expected. But num villains caught as
long to type. What if I just type that
as numbum and save it? And here I alert
numb.
If I do that, sorry, reload. I get
undefined.
And that is because num does not exist
in this object. Unlike arrays where you
can give it any name because arrays
store things in order, objects store
things by name. So that means you have
to pull them out by name. So here I do
have to say numbum villains cop. But
what if you don't really want to type
that all that many times? Well, there's
something you can do called aliasing,
meaning you give it a shorter nickname
style name. So I'm going to put a colon
here and I'm just going to call it
numbum. So I said bring out first name,
bring out last name, bring out alias,
bring out num villains caught and call
it numbum. And now when I alert numb
and reload, I get 20 because I said pull
out the attribute called numbum villains
caught and name it numbum. And now I can
alert using that. And that is how object
destructuring works.